Guide to the Donald Clifford Gallup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- February 2000 Acquisition, 1918-1964; 10; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - T. S. Eliot Papers
    - Correspondence
      - Letters to Donald Gallup
        - 107. Typed cable: SS Edinburgh Castle. One page, 18cm., 1950 February 5
          On serving on committee for Yale Library's Bollingen award.
        - 108. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 21cm., 1950 March 1
          On serving on committee for Yale Library's Bollingen award and mentioning The Cocktail Party.
        - 109. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 26cm., 1950 March 15
          On bibliographic matters.
        - 110. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 26cm., 1950 March 20
          On the Bollingen award. With typed letter, signed, from Valerie Fletcher, 28 June 1950.
        - 111. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 21cm., 1951 January 18
          Signed with initials. Faber wishes to bring out revised edition of the Eliot Bibliography. With typed letter, signed, from Valerie Fletcher, 29 Jan 1951.
        - 112. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 21cm., 1951 February 9
          On the new edition of the Bibliography.
        - 113. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 21cm., 1951 February 15
          On the new edition of the Bibliography. With typed letter, signed, from Valerie Fletcher, 4 Sept 1951, and 13 Sept 1951.
        - 114. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1951 October 1
          Signed "Tom". On the Bibliography.
        - 115. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1951 October 11
          On the Bibliography and on a possible visit to Yale.
        - 116. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1952 July 22
          On his letters to Gertrude Stein. With typed letter, signed, from secretary, 1 Sept, and another, 10 Sept 1952, from Valerie Fletcher.
        - 117. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1953 January 26
          Signed "Tom". On Cat Morgan's Apology and on reviews of Bibliography.
        - 118. Typed letter, signed: London. One page 25cm., 1953 November 26
          Signed "Tom". On The Flowers of Friendship and mentioning The Confidential Clerk. With a typed letter, signed, from Valerie Fletcher, 26 May 1954.
        - 119. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1955 April 26
          Signed "Tom". On miscellaneous matters. With a typed letter, signed, from Valerie Fletcher, 21 Feb 1956.
        - 120. Autograph letter, signed: Cambridge, Mass. One page, 28cm., 1956 May 27
          "Arrangements for my driving him and Theresa Eliot to Riverside, N. Y."
        - 121. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1956 July 10
          Offering to send American Literature and the American Language. Signed "Tom".
        - 121a. Autograph letter, signed. One page, 15 1/2cm., 1957 May 12
          Signed "Tom". On verso of announcement of his marriage.
        - 122. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1957 August 27
          Signed "Tom". "Inviting me to tea."
        - 123. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1958 October 30
          Signed "Tom". Is touched by Eliot exhibition in Yale Library.
        - 124. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1960 April 21
          Signed "Tom". Concerning recordings.
        - 125. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1960 October 5
          Signed "Tom". "Agreeing to recommend me for Guggenheim (to complete Pound Bibliography )."
        - 126. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1961 September 15
          Signed "Tom". On "A Valedictory Forbidding Mourning to the Lady of the House." Preceded by typed letter, signed, from secretary, 10 Jan 1961.
        - 127. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1962 April 24
          Signed "Tom". Requesting a second copy of "A Valedictory."
        - 128. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1962 June 27
          Signed "Tom". On the John J. Adams poems. With typed letter, signed, from secretary, 19 July 1962.
        - 129. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1962 July 25
          Signed "Tom". On "Caf‚ Cannibale" and Gus Krutzsch. With manuscript postscript by Eliot.
        - 130. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1962 August 7
          Signed "Tom". On John Adams.
        - 131. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1962 September 8
          Signed "Tom". Accepting $20 in payment for translations and on Pound bibliography. With DCG's cancelled check, endorsed by him.
        - 132. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1963 October 1
          Signed "T. S. E.". On errors in his Collected Poems.
        - 133. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1964 May 1
          Accepting honorary membership in the Elizabethan Club.
        - 134. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1964 May 3
          Signed "Tom". On various matters. With manuscript postscript by Eliot.
        - 135. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24cm., 1964 May 13
        - 136. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1964 June 10
          Signed "Tom". On plans for new edition of the Bibliography.
        - 137. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 24 1/2cm., 1964 June 22
          Signed "Tom". On plans for meeting in London in 1965.
      - Christmas cards sent to Donald Gallup
        - 137a. Special Faber & Faber card designed by Barnett Freedman, signed "T. S. Eliot". With mailing envelope addressed by a secretary, 1949 December 14
        - 137b. Special Faber card designed by Freedman, signed for Eliot, with a manuscript explanatory note by a secretary., 1950
        - 137c. Special Faber card designed by John Piper, signed "T. S. Eliot". With mailing envelope addressed by a secretary., 1951
        - 137d. Special Faber card designed by Edward Bawden, signed "T. S. Eliot". With mailing envelope addressed by a secretary., 1952 December 5
        - 137e. Special Faber card designed by Edward Ardizzone, signed "T. S. Eliot". With mailing envelope addressed by his secretary (later wife), Valerie Fletcher., 1953 December 8
        - 137f. Envelope only, addressed by T. S. Eliot. Card not present., 1953 December 10
        - 137g. Special Faber card designed by V. H. Drummond, signed "T. S. Eliot"., 1954
        - 137h. Special Faber card designed by Robin Jacques, signed "T. S. Eliot". With mailing envelope addressed by Valerie Fletcher., 1955
        - 137i. Special Faber card designed by Alan Howard, signed "T. S. Eliot". With mailing envelope addressed by Valerie Fletcher., 1956 November 30
        - 137j. Special Faber card designed by Andre Francois, signed "Tom and Valerie Eliot" ("Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With mailing envelope addressed by a secretary., 1957 December 4
        - 137k. Special Faber card designed by Gerald Rose, signed "from Valerie and T. S. Eliot" ("from Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.), 1958
        - 137l. Christmas card reproducing Crivelli's "Madonna della Candeletta," signed "from Valerie and T. S. Eliot" ("from Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With envelope addressed by a secretary., 1958 December 11
        - 137m. Christmas card reproducing Memling's "Madonna and Child, Saints and Angels," signed "from Valerie and Tom" ("from Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With envelope addressed by a secretary., 1959 November 30
        - 137n. Christmas card reproducing Marino's "Adoration des Mages," signed "from Valerie and Tom Eliot" ("from Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With envelope addressed by a secretary., 1960 December 9
        - 137o. Christmas card reproducing Luini's "L'adoration dei Tre Magi", signed "Valerie & Tom" ("Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With envelope with typed address., 1961 November 27
        - 137p. Christmas card reproducing Fra Angelico's "The Coronation of the Virgin" (detail), signed "To Donald/ Valerie and Tom" ("To Donald/Valerie" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With envelope addressed by Mrs. Eliot., 1962 December 1
        - 137q. Christmas card with printed "Greetings of the Season," explaining that Mr. and Mrs. Eliot are abroad and neither sending nor expecting Christmas cards, but wishing their friends a Happy Christmas and a Joyful New Year, with envelope addressed by a secretary., 1963 December 10
        - 137r. Christmas card reproducing Botticelli's "Adoration of the Magi," signed "To Don, from Valerie and Tom" (all except "from Tom" in Mrs. Eliot's manuscript.) With envelope addressed by a secretary., 1964 December 4
      - 138. Typed recommendation concerning Terence White Gervais: London. One page, 21cm., 1949 May 19
        Purchased Robert K. Black, 1962.
      - Letters to Alyse Gregory
        Purchased from Ms. Gregory, 1965.
        - 139. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1948 December 17
          On Scofield Thayer's poems.
        - 140. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1949 May 24
          Declining to write an introduction to Thayer's poems.
      - 141. Typed letter, signed, to Canon Cyril Hudson: London. Three pages, 26cm., 1935 October 18
        Giving comments by Faber on scheme for shop under Church auspices. "Given me by the Rev. Kenneth W. Cameron, 13 Jul 1938."
      - Letters to Edgar Jepson
        On appointments and lectures. Purchased Stonehill, 1938.
        - 142. Autograph post card, signed: London. One page, 14cm., 1919 February 5
        - 143. Autograph post card, signed. One page, 14cm., undated
        - 144. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 17 1/2cm., 1919 March 4
          Letters, 275.
        - 145. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 17 1/2cm., 1919 March 12
          Letters, 277.
        - 146. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 18cm., 1919 July 11
        - 147. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 23cm., 1919 September 22
          Letters, 332.
        - 148. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1919 October 31
          Letters, 343.
        - 149. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1919 November 3
          With Jepson's manuscript note: "Probably 3 Nov 19".
        - 150. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1919 December 13
        - 151. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1919 December 17
          With Jepson's manuscript note: "Probably 17 Dec 1919".
        - 152. Autograph letter, signed: London, "Saturday". Two pages, 22 1/2cm., 1920 February 7
          Thanks for note acknowledging gift of Ara Vus Prec.
        - 153. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1920 October 15
        - 154. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1920 December 20
        - 155. Autograph post card, signed: London. One page, 11 1/2cm., 1921 March 6
        - 156. Autograph post card, signed: London. One page, 11 1/2cm., 1921 April 20
        - 157. Autograph letter, signed: [London]. One page, 23cm., 1921 April 22
        - 158. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 23cm., 1921 May 19
        - 159. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 23cm., 1921 September 23
        - 160. Autograph post card, signed: London. One page, 11 1/2cm., 1922 April 20
        - 161. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 20 1/2cm., 1922 May 18
        - 162. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1923 February 6
        - 163. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1934 May 18
        - 164. Autograph draft of telegram to Irving Kristol, Executive Director, American Committee for Cultural Freedom: New York. One page, 14 1/2 cm., 1952 May 19
          On typed telegram from Kristol to Eliot, 1919 May 1952. Purchased from House of Books Ltd., 1952 (who had bought it from Mrs. Henry W. Eliot, Jr.)
      - 165. Typed letter, signed, to Louis L. Martz: London. One page, 20 1/2cm., 1947 June 25
        Has no objection to his saying that Eliot had pointed out to Martz importance [in Burnt Norton ] of Alice in Wonderland. Gift of Louis Martz, 1947?.
      - Letters to F. O. Matthiessen
        - 165a. Engraved Christmas greeting: London. One page., 1933 December 8
          In an envelope addressed in manuscript, postmarked as above.
        - 165b. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages. 25 1/2cm., 1934 February 8
          On memories of Eliot House and his current work: the Virginia lectures, and The Rock. With reference to Pound's "effusion" in the Advocate, and "respects" to the Matthiascat.
        - 165c. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages. 25cm., 1934 August 20
          With addressed envelope. On the publishing of his biography of Eliot, because of Eliot's objections to Fabers' publishing a book about himself, turned over to Oxford. "If they do not want it, I dare say we shall in spite of my personal protests." Looks forward to seeing the revised version and sends best wishes "for the Mathias cat and yourself."
        - 165d. Typed letter, signed: London. One page. 25 1/2cm., 1934 September 17
          On Oxford Press's publishing the Eliot biography. Mentions Ted Spencer.
        - 165e. Christmas card: [London]. One page. "from Tom Eliot"., 1934 December
          All purchased (by exchange) Horowitz, 1990.
      - Letters to Harold Monro
        Purchased 9 letters and 3 postcards, G. F. Sims, 1955. Purchased 54 items, Elkin Mathews Ltd., 1956.
        - 166. Autograph post card, signed: [London]. One page, 14 1/2cm., 1919 December 11
          Signed with initials. About an appointment.
        - 167. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1919 December 16
          About an appointment. Letters, 350.
        - 168. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 27cm., 1920 February 21
          Sending an article ("A Brief Treatise on the Criticism of Poetry").
        - 169. Autograph post card, signed: [London]. One page, 14cm., 1920 March 1
          Inquiring about article.
        - 170. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1920 March 5
          Signed with initials. Sending a revision [of part of his article?]. Letters, 370.
        - 171. Autograph letter, signed: [London?]. One page, 23cm., 1920 July 1
          On contributing to the Chapbook. Letters, 388.
        - 172. Autograph letter, signed: London, "Friday". One page, 26 1/2cm., 1920 November 6
        - 173. Autograph letter, signed: London, "Thursday". One page, 23cm., 1921
          Inviting him to tea.
        - 174. Autograph letter, signed: London "Sunday". Two pages, 9cm., 1921
          Concerning an appointment.
        - 175. Autograph letter, signed: [London?]. One page, 27cm., 1921
          Thanking him for his book.
        - 176. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1921 October 12
          On remaindering Ara Vus Prec. With typed carbon of Monro's letter to Eliot on the same subject, 8 Oct 1921. Letters, 475-76.
        - 177. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1921 November 16
          On his schedule.
        - 178. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1923 February 2
          On the Chapbook, The Sacred Wood, etc. With three manuscript corrections by Eliot.
        - 179. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1923 May 27
          On various matters. With typed carbon of Monro's reply, 28 May 1923.
        - 180. Autograph post card, signed: [London]. One page, 9cm., 1923 June 2
          On a review to be written by Monro.
        - 181. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 26 1/2cm., 1924 January 11
          With two manuscript additions by Eliot. About Monro's review-article on Wordsworth. With typed carbon of Monro's letter to Eliot, 10 Jan 1924.
        - 182. Autograph post card, signed: London. One page, 9cm., 1924 January 28
          Arranging a luncheon engagement.
        - 183. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1924 March 3
          On the Criterion.
        - 184. Typed letter, signed: Old Fishbourne. Two pages, 23cm., 1924 May 2
        - 185. Autograph post card, signed: [London]. One page, 9cm., 1924 June 6
          On an article.
        - 186. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1924 June 12
          Regretting not being able to keep an engagement because of illness; is giving up his cottage at Fishbourne.
        - 187. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1924 July 9
          On reviewing for the Criterion. Typed carbon of Monro's reply on verso. Signed with initials.
        - 188. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1924 August 5
          Signed with initials. On the Wordsworth review.
        - 189. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1924 August 28
          Signed with initials. More on the Wordsworth review.
        - 190. Typed postcard, signed: London. One page, 9cm., 1924 October 10
          Regretting failure to attend Criterion Club meetings.
        - 191. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1924 November 15
          Signed with initials. Asking for suggestions. With typed carbon of Monro's letter to Eliot of 15 November 1924 and with typed summary (at head of Eliot's letter) of Monro's reply, 18 Nov 1924. With typed letter, signed, from secretary (I. P. Fassett), 21 Nov 1924.
        - 192. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1925 March 14
          Signed with initials. Regretting, for his wife, having to refuse an engagement. With manuscript postscript by Eliot on envelope. With typed carbon of Monro's reply, 3 April 1925.
        - 193. Autograph post card, signed: [London]. One page, 9cm., 1925 April 6
          Signed with initials. Thanks for his letter.
        - 194. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 17cm., 1925 April 25
          On his contributing to the Chapbook. With typed carbon of Monro's letter, 22 April 1925, and of his reply 7 May 1925, with manuscript postscript.
        - 195. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1925 June 12
          Signed with initials. On his wife's health. With typed copy of Monro's reply, 1 July 1925, with ms. addition.
        - 196. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1925 July 7
          Signed with initials. On contributing to the Chapbook. With manuscript note by Monro "Not answered."
        - 197. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 23cm., 1925 October 20
          Regretting not being able to accept an invitation.
        - 198. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26cm., 1926 June 24
          On the Commerce agency in England. With typed carbon of Monro's reply, 28 June 1926.
        - 199. Typed letter, signed: Paris. Two pages, 26 1/2cm., 1926 July
          Signed with initials. On the Commerce matter and on Criterion dinners.
        - 200. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1928 February 17
          Signed with initials. On Criterion reviews.
        - 201. Autograph letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1928 May 15
          Signed with initials. Thanking him for his letter.
        - 202. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 26 1/2cm., 1928 June 25
          Signed with initials. On various matters.
        - 203. Typed postcard, signed: London. One page, 9cm., 1928 October 19
          Signed with initials. On a review.
        - 204. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1928 November 20
          Signed with initials. On Criterion dinner guest-list.
        - 205. Typed letter, signed: London, "Monday". One page, 23 cm., 1928 December
          Signed with initials. On arranging meeting with Frost.
        - 206. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1928 December 17
          Signed with initials. Concerning Miss Evelyn Hardy.
        - 207. Typed postcard, signed: London. One page, 9cm., 1929
          Signed with initials. Making an appointment.
        - 208. Typed postcard, signed: London. One page, 9cm., 1929 April 18
          Inviting him to dinner.
        - 209. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 25 1/2cm., 1929 April 29
          On a poem by Desmond Harmsworth, a reading, and cancelling dinner party.
        - 210. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 27cm., 1929 October 18
          Inquiring about promised review of Richard [Aldington]'s poems. With typed carbon of Monro's reply, 23 Oct 1929.
        - 211. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm. On various matters., 1930 May 14
          Signed "Tom".
        - 212. Autograph note, signed: [London?]. One page, 9 1/2cm., 1930 August 28
          Note of dinner engagement.
        - 213. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 27cm., 1932 January 1
          Signed with initials. On a pork pie and arranging an appointment.
        - 214. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 27cm., 1932 February 17
          Signed "Tom". Sending check and reporting on Criterion evening.
      - Letters to Mrs. Harold Monro
        Purchased G. F. Sims, 1956.
        - 215. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 15 1/2cm., 1933 September 1
          Signed "Tom". Arranging an appointment.
        - 216. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 18cm., 1934 February 25
          Signed with initials. On salad.
        - 217. Typed letter: incomplete? London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1934 January 13
          Giving addresses of people in U. S. for her to look up. With typed letter, signed, to her from Henry W. Eliot, Jr., 2 Apr 1934.
        - 218. Autograph letter, signed: London. Two pages, 18cm., 1934 December 13
          Signed with initials. Is happy to have Monro's bookcase.
        - 219. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1935 March 28
          Signed "Tom." Inviting her to tea.
        - 220. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1935 April 12
          Signed "Tom". About her work, For Your Delight.
        - 221. Typed letter, signed: London. Three pages, 25 1/2cm., 1935 May 2
          Signed "Tom". About For Your Delight, and her other books.
        - 222. Typed letter, signed: London. Two pages, 25 1/2cm., 1935 May 9
          Signed "Tom". On the agreement for publication of For Your Delight.
        - 223. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 25 1/2cm., 1935 July 5
          Signed "Tom". On Murder in the Cathedral and Charlotte Mew.
        - 224. Autograph letter, signed: Midhurst, Sussex. Two pages, 21cm., 194-? August 2
          Signed "Tom". On various matters and on the difficulty of visiting Fire- brave Kennels.
      - 225. Typed letter, signed, to F. C. Owlett: London. One page, 26 1/2cm., 1927 December 7
        Returning his article because Criterion is to cease. Purchased Bertram Rota Ltd.
      - Letters to Derek Parker
        Purchased Bertram Rota Ltd.
        - 226. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 20 1/2cm., 1959 June 11
          On publication of a selection of Ezra Pound's essays.
        - 227. Typed letter, signed: London. One page, 20cm., 1959 June 26
          On publication of an anthology of contemporary religious verse.
      - Letters to Brigit Patmore
        Purchased Jacob Schwartz, 1954.
        - 228. Autograph letter, signed: London. Three pages, 18cm., 1919 May 4
          Signed with initials. Arranging an appointment. With autograph letter, signed, from Vivien Eliot, "Tuesday" referring to the same appointment. Letters 290-91.
        - 229. Autograph letter, signed: London, "Wednesday". Two pages, 18cm., 1919 May?
          Signed with initials. Arranging an appointment.
        - 230. Typed letter, signed: "Monday". One page, 26 1/2cm., 1919 May?
          Signed with initials. Arranging an appointment. Letters, 291.
        - 231. Autograph letter, signed: London, "Wednesday". Four pages, 18cm., 1919 May 14?